好了  这是全新的一天
All right, it's a new day.
关于瑞秋的那件事呢
All that stuff about Rachel?
现在你没那种感觉了  那简直太疯狂了
You don't feel that now. It was crazy.
你没事  你好的不得了
You're fine. You're better than fine.
你就像朋友汤尼说的那样  "棒极了"
You are, as your friend Tony would say, "Great!"
一切都很正常
Everything's normal.
她只是你的朋友  瑞秋
She's just your friend, Rachel.
你的朋友瑞秋
Your friend, Rachel.
Your friend. Rachel.
嗨  亲爱的
Hi, sweetie.
嗨  她是你女朋友瑞秋
Hey, it's your girlfriend, Rachel!
《老友记》  第八季  第13集  钱德的泡泡浴
Friends S08E13 The One Where Chandler Takes a Bath
你...你磕嗨了吗
Are you...? Are you high?
我刚刚泡了一个超舒服的澡
I just had the most amazing bath.
真的吗  我不喜欢泡澡
Really? I don't like baths.
你喜欢跟我泡鸳鸯浴啊
Wait. You like them with me.
亲爱的  我喜欢的不是泡澡
Honey, it's not the bath I enjoy.
我是喜欢看全身湿答答的裸体女人
It's the wet, naked lady.
泡澡能让你全身放松
Baths are so relaxing.
真的吗  你在里面做什么
Really? What do you do?
不过是坐在浴缸里  泡着自己洗过的脏水
You just sit in there, stewing in your own filth.
你觉得我能有多脏呢
How dirty do you think I am?
如果你点上蜡烛
I'm telling you if you had some candles
配上泡泡跟音乐  你一定会爱上泡澡
and some bubbles and some music, you would love it.
能帮你解除压力  一身轻松
It would take all of your stress away.
现在是星期三下午两点  我正在看越野单车赛
Honey, it's 2:00 on a Wednesday and I'm watching Road Rules.
你觉得我的压力会有多大
How stressed do you think I am?
钱德勒
Hey, Chandler.
你有空吗  我真的需要跟你谈一谈
You got a minute? I really need to talk to you.
好  这场谈话是要配冷披萨
Oh, yeah. Is this a coldpizza talk
还是配剩肉卷
or a leftovermeat loaf talk?
都不是
Well, neither.
天啊  发生了什么大事
Oh, my God, what's up?
我不知道  只是...
I don't know. It's just...
最近我觉得...
Lately, I've been feeling...
好吧  事情是这样的
Okay, here's what it is.
你知道吗  我觉得好多了  谢谢
You know what? I feel a lot better. Thanks.
快回来告诉我
Just come back.
好吧
Okay.
你跟莫妮卡当了很久的朋友
You and Monica, friends for a long time.
当然这是有规则的
And sure, there are rules.
之后你们去了伦敦
But then you went to London.
可是那不一样
But that's different.
这也是有规则的  你理解我的意思吗
There are rules there too, you know what I mean?
你自己理解吗
Do you?
你们的情况和我不一样
It was different for you guys.
你们刚好在同一个地方  对吧
I mean, you were both in the same place, right?
在伦敦  对
In London?  Yeah.
对  莫妮卡跟我在伦敦时我们刚好都在那里
Yes, when Monica and I were in London, we were both in London.
我就不该来找你
You know what. This is a bad idea.
算了  就当我什么都没说
Forget it. Forget all about it.
帮我个忙  别把这件事说出去
And listen, do me a favor, this conversation between you and me.
我会尽力的
If that.
罗斯  别忘了明天我们要一起去产检
Oh, Ross, don't forget we have that doctor's appointment tomorrow.
好  你们要知道宝宝的性别了吗
Right.  Hey, are you going to find out the sex of the baby?
不  我们不想知道
No. We talked about it. We don't wanna know.
我们只在乎宝宝是不是健康快乐
All we care about is that it's happy and healthy.
对  健康快乐  还有可爱
Yep, happy and healthy. And cute.
聪明  万人迷
And smart.  Popular.
还要有科学精神
With an aptitude for science.
你们两个说的是同一个宝宝吗
Are you two talking about the same baby?
你们开始想名字了吗
Hey, have you thought of names yet?
对  我想到一大堆
Oh, yeah. I've come up with a bunch of ideas.
真的吗  我也是  我也是
Really? Me too.  Me too.
真的吗
Really?
如果是女孩就叫菲比  如果是男孩就叫菲宝
If it's a girl, Phoebe. And if it's a boy, Pheebo.
或许吧
Maybe.
但多想些备用名字应该有益无害
But it wouldn't hurt to have a backup, you know?
瑞秋  你都想到什么名字  好吧
Rach, what were you thinking?  Okay.
我想如果是女孩
I was thinking if it's a girl...
叫她珊德妮好吗  这是法文
...how about Sandrene? It's French.
很适合做工业溶剂公司的名字
That's a really pretty name for an industrial solvent.
好吧  你想到什么
Okay, fine. What do you have?
我想到一个男孩的名字
It's for a boy.
我知道起这个名字有点疯狂
I know it's a little out there, but...
达尔文
...Darwin.
天啊  我们的孩子会在操场上被打死
Oh, my God. Our child will be beaten to death in the schoolyard.
对  被珊德妮打死
Yeah, by Sandrene.
你那么说是因为我不喜欢你想的名字
You're just saying that because I said no to your name.
我是本来就不喜欢
I'm really, really not.
你们各有五次否决权  如何
How about you each get five vetoes?
听起来很公平
That sounds fair.
不过我觉得你根本用不着否决  听着
I don't think you'll need it though. Check this out.
如果是女孩就叫小雨
If it's a girl, Rain.
否决
Veto.
为什么
Why?
小雨  "嗨  我叫小雨
Rain? "Hi, my name is Rain.
我有自己的炉子  我的衣服是用麦子做的"
I have my own kiln, and my dress is made out of wheat."
我认识她
I know her!
我在死人秀里跟她买了一块手工肥皂
I bought a homemade soap from her at a Dead show!
好  如果是男孩就叫撒切尔
Okay. How about for a guy, Thatcher?
罗斯  你为什么那么恨我们的孩子
Ross, why do you hate our child?
好吧  轮到你了  詹姆斯
Fine, you go.  Okay. James.
如果是女孩的话  否决
But only if it's a girl.  Veto.
我喜欢萝丝  你觉得呢
How about... I like Ruth. What about Ruth?
抱歉  难道我们的宝宝89岁了吗
Oh, I'm sorry. Are we having an 89yearold?
戴顿呢  否决  斯图亚特
How about Dayton?  Veto. Stewart.
否决  索耶
Veto. Sawyer.
否决  海伦  否决
Veto. Helen.  Veto.
你们没觉得"否决"这个名字很好听吗
Is it me, or is Veto starting to sound really good?
天啊  我为你准备了一个大惊喜
Boy, do I have a surprise for you.
在阳台上做爱吗
Sex on the balcony?
不  但某人一直放不下这个念头是吧
No. But someone's really not gonna get over that idea, are they?
怎么了  我帮你放了洗澡水
What is it?  I drew you a bath.
我不喜欢泡澡
I don't like baths.
你愿意跟我去阳台上做爱吗
Could you draw me a picture of us having sex on the balcony?
拜托你试试看  我使出了全部绝招
Please. Will you just try it for me. I used all my best stuff.
我点了蜡烛  放了音乐
I lit some candles, I put on some music.
用了浴盐跟泡泡浴
I used bath salts, plus bubble bath.
我还帮你找了个海军模型船
And got you this little plastic Navy ship!
体现你的男性雄风
So it's a boy bath.
确实稍微增添了点男人味
This does butch it up a bit.
我发誓你试过后一定会爱上泡澡的
I swear, if you try it, you will love it.
如果我答应泡澡
If I do this,
我们能不能至少讨论在阳台上做爱的事
can we at least discuss sex on the balcony?
当然可以
Absolutely.
但我知道那场讨论会如何进行
But I know how that discussiors gonna go.
好吧  还不赖
All right, this isn't so bad.
我喜欢花香味
I like the flowery smell.
这没什么不妥  因为我手上有船
Which is okay, because I've got my boat.
怎么样  我的天啊
So?  Oh, my God.
我就说过你会喜欢泡澡嘛
I told you you were a bath person.
等你洗完  我可以帮你做脸
Hey, when you get out, maybe I can give you a facial.
我需要一艘更雄伟的船
I'm gonna need a bigger boat.
我觉得你对萝丝这个名字不够开通
I don't think you had an open mind about the name Ruth.
拜托嘛  小萝丝·盖勒  多可爱啊
I mean, come on, little Ruthie Geller? How cute is that?
天啊  我仿佛听到了搓麻将的声音
Oh, my God, I can practically hear the mahjong tiles.
好了  检查结果都很正常
Okay. All your tests look fine.
你们想知道宝宝的性别吗
Are you two interested in knowing the sex of the baby?
我们不想知道
No, we're not.
但病历里面有记录
But you have it right there in that file?
你可以告诉我们是男孩或是女孩
You could tell us whether it's a boy or a girl?
戴顿或珊德妮  菲比或菲宝
Dayton or Sandrene? Phoebe or Pheebo?
没错  如果你们不想知道
That's right. But if you don't wanna know...
不  我们愿意等  对吧  对
No, we wanna wait. Right?  Right. Right.
我马上回来
Oh, I'll be right back.
我知道自己不该多嘴
I know it's really not my place...
但请不要给宝宝取名叫菲宝
...but please don't name your child Pheebo.
你觉得哪个宝宝最丑
So which of these babies do you think is the ugliest?
什么  瑞秋  你这么说太恶毒了
What? Rach, come on, that's terrible.
他们是宝宝  都很可爱
They're babies. They're all beautiful.
左起第三个
Third one from the left?
对  他为什么要盯着我看
Yeah. Why is it staring at me?
他大概知道我在说他坏话
I think it knows I'm talking about it.
你不...  怎么了
Don't you...?  What?
你在偷看
You're looking!
我没有  我看到了
I didn't!  I saw you!
好吧  我在偷看  但我什么都没有看到
Fine, I did, but I didn't see anything. I swear.
你太可耻了  丑宝宝唾弃你
Shame on you! Ugly baby judges you!
好吧  听我说  我没有...
Okay. But Ross, listen to me, I didn't...
别告诉我  我不想知道
No, no. Don't tell me! I don't wanna know!
我想说也没办法  因为我也不知道
I couldn't even if I wanted to, because I don't know!
我发誓我什么都没看到
I swear I didn't see anything!
我不想知道  刚刚我是一时糊涂
I don't want to know. It was just a momentary lapse.
一时糊涂
Momentary lapse?
你不懂得自制吗
Don't you have any selfcontrol?
好吧  你要是能早几个月做这场说教就好了
Okay. A couple months late on the lecture, Ross.
我回来了
Hello?
我在浴室  你能进来一下吗
I'm in the bathroom. Can you come in here?
我觉得不太对劲
I think there's something wrong.
我还是在这里等着吧
You know what? I think I'll wait out here.
我在浴缸里
I'm in the bathtub.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我自己放了洗澡水  但方法不对
I drew my own bath, but I did it wrong.
水不冷不热  浴盐没有溶解
The water's tepid, the salt didn't dissolve
现在都结块了
and is now lodged places.
我用的几种香料闻起来很不协调
And the scents I used don't compliment each other.
桉树加甘菊
Eucalyptus and chamomile?
怎么了  浴盐
What?  Bath salts.
开始冒泡了
They're starting to effervesce.
感觉完全不同
It's different.
这感觉真有意思
It's interesting.
好吧  我们谈谈别的事吧
Okay. Let's talk about something else.
好  今天你过得还好吧
Yeah. Sure. So, what was going on with you today?
乔伊今天跟我聊了一些很奇怪的事情
I actually had the weirdest conversation with Joey.
他谈到规则  还有对错
He was talking about rules and right and wrong.
我也跟他谈过这些
I had the exact same conversation.
是吗  他到底在说什么
You did? What was he talking about?
自从他演过《麦克白》之后
I don't know. Joey hasn't had this much trouble
我还没见过他说不出话的样子
getting out words since we saw him in Macbeth.
那可真是漫长的一夜
That was a long night.
好吧  我们来分析一下
All right, let's break this down.
他到底跟你说了什么
What exactly did he say to you?
他说到规则
Okay. He was talking about rules
对别人有了不同的感觉
and looking at people differently.
他没有跟我说那个问题
He didn't say anything about that to me.
他跟你说了什么
What'd he tell you?
他问到你跟我在伦敦发生的事
He was asking all this questions about you, me and London.
从头至尾都在谈规则
And of course the glue that holds this all together, the rules.
好吧  你跟我在伦敦
Okay. So you, me and London.
对别人有不同的感觉
Looking at people differently.
或许他想跟某人发生你跟我在伦敦所做的事
Maybe he wants to do what you and I did in London with someone.
但他说"规则"是什么意思
But what'd he mean by "rules"?
等一下  菲比走进来时  他就不说了
Wait a minute. He stopped talking the minute Phoebe came in.
因为他对她的感觉不同了
Because he was looking at her differently.
菲比是他的朋友
And Phoebe is his friend.
他觉得那样违反了规则
So he thinks that would be breaking the rules.
天啊  他想跟菲比在伦敦上床
My God, he wants to do it with Phoebe in London!
你们在哪里  等一下
You guys?  Just a minute!
崔比安尼太太来了
That's Mrs. Tribbiani.
什么都别说
You don't say anything.
我为什么要说
Why would I say anything?
我们的两个好朋友
That two of our friends could start
就要展开一段伟大恋情
the greatest love affair of their lives?
他们将来可要谢我
They would have me to thank.
然后我们可以一起开始怀孕生孩子
Then we could all start having babies!
我不准你告诉她
I'm not gonna let you say anything.
你就待在这里
You just stay here.
天啊
Oh, God!
莫妮卡  我拿熨斗来还你
Hey, Monica, I brought back your iron.
是你拿走的吗  我还以为我弄丢了
Oh, you had that? I thought I lost it.
一个月前  我买了个新的
I got a new one a month ago.
太好了  我把这个弄坏了
Oh, just as well. I broke this one.
怎么  没事
What?  Nothing.
好吧
Okay.
我实在不该说  我不该说出来的
I really shouldn't say. I'm really not supposed to.
好吧
Fine.
这可是个好消息
It's a humdinger.
可惜你不能告诉我
Well, then it's really too bad that you can't tell me.
有人喜欢你
Somebody likes you!
是钱德勒吗
Is it Chandler?
不是  那叫他别再盯着我看了
No!  Then tell him to stop staring.
是乔伊
It's Joey.
真的吗  乔伊  看不出来啊
Really? Joey? You don't say.
你对他有意思吗
Is it something you'd be interested in?
我不知道  我不知道
I don't know, I don't know. I don't know.
我一方面会想"天啊  我可以跟他在一起吗"
You know, I mean, on the one hand, "Mother, may I?"
但另一方面
But, you know, on the other hand...
不行  我们是朋友
No. No, I can't. We're friends.
不行  我不能拿我们现在的友谊冒险
Oh, no. I don't wanna risk what we have.
你说得有道理
I guess that makes sense.
你要跟他谈一谈吗
You think you're gonna talk to him?
当然  他可是乔伊
Sure. I mean, it's Joey.
我不希望他受伤害
I don't want him to get hurt.
我简直是势不可挡啊
Well, I must say, I am on fire!
先是钱德勒  现在又是乔伊
First Chandler, now Joey.
没有钱德勒  只有乔伊  好吧
Not Chandler. Just Joey.  Sure.
你知道吗  我想过了
You know what? I've been thinking about it.
我开始接受萝丝这个名字了
I'm really coming around on the name Ruth.
我觉得可以考虑帮孩子取那个名字
I think I would actually consider naming our child that.
瑞秋  这对我来说简直意义重大
Rach, I can't tell you how much that means to me.
等一下
Wait a minute.
等一下  你之前很讨厌萝丝这个名字
Wait a minute. You hated the name Ruth.
你为什么会改变心意
Why would you change your mind?
除非你知道我们根本用不上它
Unless you know we're never gonna have to use it.
你看到病历了  知道自己怀的是男孩
You did see the folder. You know it's a boy!
我什么都没有看到
I didn't see anything.
我真的是改变了心意
I actually changed my mind about the name.
我可不觉得  你答应让我选萝丝
I don't think so. You're giving me Ruth...
如果你生了儿子 你就能帮他取名字了
...so you get to name him when it's a boy.
到时候你会决定叫他海瑟
That's when you'll swoop in and name him Heath
布兰恩或史奎亚
or Blaine or Sequoia.
我会...史奎亚
I would... Sequoia!
否决  好吧
Veto.  Fine.
除非...
Unless...
你知道我会看穿你的阴谋
...you anticipated that I would figure all this out...
而你知道自己怀的是女孩
...and you know that it actually is a girl.
你真的希望她叫萝丝
And you really do want her to be named Ruth.
我才不会上当  好吧
Well, I'm not falling for that! Okay?
不要考虑萝丝了
Ruth is off the table!
可是你想给孩子取这个名字啊
But, Ross, you want the name Ruth.
我不会让你得逞
Not like this!
怎么了
What's up?
乔伊  我知道了  什么
Joey, I know.  What?
我知道了  什么
I know.  What?
我知道你的心思了
I know about your feelings.
天啊  真的吗
Oh, my God, did you?
对不起  虽然钱德勒跟莫妮卡终成眷属了
Yes. I'm sorry. I know things worked out for Chandler and Monica,
但那是少之又少的例子
but that's rare.
我知道  比起他们的情况
I know. And this is so much more complicated
我的情况复杂多了
than it was for those guys.
她可是瑞秋啊
I mean, it's Rachel, for God's sakes.
天啊  是瑞秋
For God's sakes, it's Rachel!
就是嘛  她不只是我的朋友
I know! She's not only my friend,
她还怀孕了
she's my pregnant friend.
她不仅怀孕了  还是罗斯的前女友
She's my pregnant friend who's Ross' ex!
对  那是瑞秋
Yeah, that's Rachel.
我哪能比得上她
Beat me over the head with it.
我该怎么办
What am I gonna do?
我努力克服对她的这种感觉
I keep trying to get rid of these feelings.
昨晚我整夜没睡
I stayed up all last night
写出所有我不喜欢她的地方
and made a list of everything I don't like about her.
你想听听看吗  好
You wanna hear it?  Yeah.
"她要我改吃低卡美乃滋"
"She made me switch to light mayo."
没了  我只想到这点
That's it! That's all I got!
其实低卡的味道一样  而且我的裤腰变松了
You know what? Tastes the same and my pants fit better.
乔伊  我觉得你是庸人自扰
Joey, I think you're getting upset for nothing.
或许你对她只是一时好感
This is probably just a crush.
你真的那么觉得吗
You think?
没错  你对她顿生好感
Absolutely. You get this rush of feelings,
但那种感觉会消失
but then it goes away.
对  我对她只是一时好感
Yeah, just a crush. That's all this is.
一时好感
It's a crush!
我是乔伊  我才不会玩真的
I'm Joey. I don't get deep feelings.
就是嘛  这种情况经常发生
Right. There you go. Crushes happen all the time.
我对你们三个男生也有过那种感觉
I know I've had them for all you guys.
除了罗斯跟钱德勒
Except for Ross and Chandler.
我相信你对我们三个也是  不尽然
And I'm sure you've had them for us.  Not really.
你就不能可怜可怜我
Throw me a bone here.
我打电话给医生了
So I called the doctor.
现在我们都知道宝宝的性别了
Now we both know the sex of the baby.
什么
What?
没错  我青出于蓝胜于蓝
That's right. The student has become the master.
罗斯  我发誓我真的不知道
Ross, I swear. I don't know.
少来了  你知道是个女孩
Oh, come on, you know it's a girl.
什么
A what?
你真的不知道
You really didn't know?
我们要有女儿了  不
We're having a girl?  No.
你就是那么说的  不
That's what you said.  No.
你说是女孩  是  我真的很抱歉
You said girl.  Yes. I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
没关系  我们要有女儿了
I'm not! We're having a girl!
有时候我不敢相信孩子他爸是你
Sometimes I can't believe it's with you,
但我们要有女儿了
but still, we're having a girl!
我知道  你知道吗
I know! You know what?
我要重新考虑萝丝这个名字
I'm putting Ruth back on the table.
好  我们要生下小萝丝了
Yes, we'll have ourselves a little baby Ruth.
请求否决  好吧  否决
Permission to veto.  Yes, please.
这是精油味吗
Do I smell essential oils?
对  我要泡澡  我先去拿本杂志
Yeah. I'm gonna take a bath. I was just gonna get a magazine.
好
Okay.
你这是干嘛呢
What do you think you're doing?
忘却烦恼
Leaving my troubles behind?
我知道你是新手
I know that you're new at this,
但这不合乎泡澡的礼仪
but this is unacceptable bath decorum.
身心如此放松  我还哪顾得上那么多礼仪
It's so hard to care when you're this relaxed.
好吧  你可以泡澡  但我要拿走你的船
Okay, fine. You can have the bath, but I am taking your boat.
现在你只是个爱洗澡的女生
Now you're just a girl in a tub.
泡泡浴  太有男子气概了
Hi, bubbles. Manly.
我想顺道过来
I thought I would drop by
告诉你我和乔伊的结果
and let you know how it went with Joey.
你跟她说了
You told her?
是她自己问出来的
She pulled it out of me!
她真的很会套别人的话
She's like a conversational wizard!
结果如何
How did it go?
你错了  他不喜欢我  什么
You were wrong. He doesn't like me.  What?
如果我让你去找李·梅杰斯
Yeah. How would you like it if I sent you to Lee Majors' house...
我告诉你他喜欢你  结果你跑过去
...and I told you he liked you and you went there...
发现他根本不喜欢你
...and you found out that he didn't like you.
你会有什么感觉
How would you feel?
我不会在乎
I don't think I'd care.
真的吗  李梅杰很性感
Really? Lee Majors is hot.
有人吗  我们在浴室里
Hello?  We're in the bathroom!
为什么  因为现在是放松享受时间
Why?  Because it's a relaxing and enjoyable time!
你们在这里做什么  天啊
What are you guys doing in here?  Oh, my God.
他对一个朋友有了不同的感觉  但不是菲比
A friend he's looking at differently, but it's wrong.
是瑞秋  你喜欢瑞秋
It's Rachel!  You like Rachel?
这不是什么大事  菲比跟我谈过
Look. It's no big deal, okay? Phoebe and I talked about it.
我对她只是一时好感  这种感觉会消失的
It's just a crush. It's gonna go away.
哥们  你该拿泡泡遮一遮了
Dude, you gotta rearrange your bubbles.
恭喜你
Mazel tov.
我和罗斯在找你们
Ross and I were looking for you.
我们都在这里做什么  天啊
What are we all doing in here? Oh, my.
亲爱的  用船遮遮羞
Honey, cover it up with the boat.
有人吗
Hello?
我们都在这里  欢迎你加入我们
Yes. We're all in here, and we'd love for you to join us!
发生了什么事
Well, hey! What's going on?
船不错啊  看错了
Oh, cool boat. Oh, no.
你告诉他们了吗  没有  我在等你
Did you tell them?  No. I was waiting for you.
告诉我们什么  我怀的是女儿
Tell us what?  We're having a girl.
哇  真的吗
Oh, wow! Really?
我待会再跟你们一起庆祝
I'll get you later.
好吧  又是全新的一天
All right. It's a new day.
那只是一时好感
And it's just a crush.
没错  只是一时好感
That's all. Just a little crush.
我到底在担心什么  简直不可理喻
All that worrying I was doing? That was crazy. Crazy.
就像这只小鸟朋友说的那样  "太疯狂了"
Like my friend the bird here would say, "It was cuckoo!"
一切都会没事  那只是一时好感
Everything's gonna be fine. It's just a crush.
嗨  亲爱的  我爱你
Hi, sweetie.  I love you.
洗鸳鸯浴感觉很棒吧
It's nice to do this together, isn't it?
对  你让我感觉非常好
Yeah. And what you're doing feels so good.
我没有碰你
I'm not touching you.
是吗  是浴盐在起作用
You're not?  It's the salts.
天啊  简直是享受新境界
Oh, sweet Lord, new realms of pleasure.
只要能让你忘记阳台的事就行  大男人
Whatever keeps you off the balcony, big guy.